rzim.org 2018-10-12

# RZIM Privacy Policy | RZIM

At Ravi Zacharias International Ministries, Inc. (RZIM) we are committed to protecting and maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of our donors and online users. We aim to develop or use technologies that give you the safest communication and online experience. This Statement of Privacy governs and applies to all personal and anonymous data collection and usage, including but not limited to, event registration, mailing lists, website, and e-commerce.

**Awareness**

RZIM considers it important to disclose its Donor Privacy Policy to make you aware of the way your information is used. We also provide you with the opportunity to remove your name from our mailing list, if you desire to do so.

**What is Personal Information?**

For this Privacy Policy, personal information is information about you, individually, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information, and your personal preferences, interests (including religious views), and other information you may share with us.

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

RZIM also collects anonymous demographic information, which includes but is not limited to your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and favorites.

In addition, we collect the personal information that you submit to our websites, such as your name, address and any other contact or other information that you choose to provide. Collection may occur, for example, when you:

  * Use the “contact” portion of our website;
  * Make a donation or online purchase, resulting in an appropriate receipt;
  * Receive and review online information about our ministries;
  * Apply for a position or to volunteer through our website;
  * Request resources, book an event, or
  * Correspond with a representative of RZIM.

There is also anonymous information that is automatically collected by our web server. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information may be used by RZIM for the operation of the service to maintain the quality of the service and to provide general statistics regarding use of the RZIM website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through RZIM public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. (Note: RZIM does not read any of your private online communications.)

RZIM encourages you to review the statements of websites you choose to link to from RZIM so that you can understand how those websites collect, use, and share your information. RZIM is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the RZIM and RZIM family of websites.

Where you request information from us, we may use the e-mail address that you provide to send you information about our ministry and resources that may be of interest to you. If you have agreed to receive communications from us, such as by e-mail, you may ask us to remove you from the list at any time using the unsubscribe instructions provided with each e-mail.

If you wish to be removed from our conventional mailing list, please contact us at 1-800-448-6766.

**Use of Your Personal Information**

RZIM collects and uses your personal information to operate the RZIM website and deliver services you have requested. We use your information to help you complete a transaction, communicate with you, and to update you on ministry happenings. Credit card numbers are used only for donation or payment processing and are not retained for other purposes. RZIM also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from RZIM and RZIM offices located outside of the United States. RZIM may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Furthermore, personal information collected through our website is used and disclosed for our ministry and business purposes. For example, we may collect, use and disclose your personal information to:

  * Establish, maintain and manage our relationship with you and fulfill orders that have been requested;
  * Be able to review the products and services that we provide to you so that we may work to improve our products and services;
  * Be able to comply with your requests;
  * Protect us against error, fraud, theft, and damage to our property; and
  * Enable us to comply with applicable law or regulatory process (for example, we may collect personal information to satisfy the obligations imposed on us by various regulators).
  * Communicate with you about our ministry and resources which may be of interest to you.

RZIM does not sell, rent, or lease its donor or user lists to third parties. RZIM may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to RZIM, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. RZIM will not send mailings to donors or users on behalf of other organizations.

RZIM keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within RZIM, to determine what RZIM services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within RZIM to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

RZIM websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on RZIM or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of RZIM; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RZIM, or the public.

**Use of Cookies**

The RZIM websites use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize RZIM pages, or register with RZIM’s site or services, a cookie helps RZIM to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same RZIM website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the RZIM features that you customized.

You can accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the RZIM services or websites you visit.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

RZIM secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. RZIM secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while this website strives to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once this website receives your transmission, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

**Children’s Online Privacy**

We are concerned about the privacy of young children, and we do not collect any more personal information than is reasonably necessary to enable them to participate in the activities we offer on our sites. RZIM will not knowingly collect or preserve data from children under 16 years of age. We encourage you to become involved with your child’s Internet activities and their access to our site, to ensure that his or her privacy is well protected. To read more about online safety and how to become more involved with your child’s online experience, visit OnGuardOnline.gov.

**Updating Your Personal Information**

It is important that the information contained in our records is both accurate and current. If your personal information happens to change during our relationship, please keep us informed of such changes. In some circumstances, we may not agree with your request to change your personal information and will instead append an alternative text to the record in question.

**Changes to this Statement** ** **

RZIM will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect your feedback. RZIM encourages you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how RZIM is protecting your information.

**Contact Information**

RZIM welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that RZIM has not adhered to this statement, please contact RZIM at [rzim@rzim.org](mailto:rzim@rzim.org). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to determine and remedy the problem promptly.

_Last updated: May 24, 2018_
